

Sayali Parkar

Date of birth: 29/04/1995 | Nationality: Indian | Gender: Female | Phone number: (+91) 9764326155 (Mobile) |

Email address: spark.sp28@gmail.com | Website: www.linkedin.com/in/sayali-parkar-9b02b9199 | Website:

https://github.com/parkarsayali | Address: Mumbai, India (Home)

About me:

Dedicated Full stack web developer with 2 + years of experience in achieving tangible results and cross-team collaboration. Proactive and excited to partner with like-minded individuals to achieve goals and creating solutions using MERN stack skillset.

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/08/2021 - 03/11/2022 Bangalore, India

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER MENDIOS TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD

- Wrote and defined clean codes to achieve functional and sustainable web applications using ReactJS.
- Assisted in development through planning, designing, creating and testing.
- Created responsive design frontend layouts using Material UI, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and JQuery, aiding smooth customer experiences.
- Worked with axios to establish communication between React apps and APIs.
- Used **React Query**, which is a ReactJS preconfigured data management library which gives you power and control over server-side state management, fetching, and caching of data, and error handling in a simple and declarative way without affecting the global state of your application.
- Provided complete technical documentation, code comments and readable code, properly storing in central documentation library.
- Optimised images effectively to improve overall SEO, increasing website reach and brand awareness.
- Collaborated with designers effectively to assess application requirements and advise on technical solutions.
- Trained a fresher.

28/01/2020 - 10/10/2020 Mumbai, India

FRONT END DEVELOPER ASPIRING MEDIA TECH

- Built website Frontend using HTML ,CSS ,Bootstrap,
- Added functionality for smooth UX using JavaScript, JQuery.
- Designed and implemented **Responsive Web Design** for mobile, desktop and tablets.
- Scheduled meetings with clients to discuss website design preference and requirements.
- Collaborated with designers to implement concept and design of website.

01/06/2019 - 27/08/2019 Mumbai, India

RPA DEVELOPER YASHUSS UNLIMITED PVT LTD

• Worked on Robotic Process Automation using automation anywhere.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

India

BACHELORS OF ENGINEERING (INFT)

Address India

India

HIGHER SECONDARY EDUCATION

Address India

SECONDARY EDUCATION

Address India

DIGITAL SKILLS

Reactjs | Material UI | React Hooks, React Router & React Redux | React Query | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | JavaScript | Github | JQuery | Postman | Object-Oriented Programming | RESTful api AXIOS | React Beautiful DND | Es6 | Web Development | Async programming(async await) | React Typescript (beginner) | API Integrations | MongoDB | Nodejs | basic figma | Cypress testing (beginner) | React Code-splitting

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PROJECTS

01/01/2023 - 02/01/2023

Expense Tracker This is an expense tracker application that uses **ReactJs** for frontend and **context APIs** and **hooks** for state management.

Link https://github.com/parkarsayali/expense_tracker

29/12/2022 - 31/12/2022

Recipe App

- This recipe app uses Reactls , Material UI, for frontend.
- It uses react-splide, react-slides to add the image slider.
- It fetches different recipes via API Integration

Link https://github.com/parkarsayali/recipe-app

07/12/2022 - CURRENT

Memories App

- This is a MERN stack application which uses Nodels, express, MongoDB for backend.
- The frontend layout is designed using ReactJs, Material UI.
- It uses Context API for state management.
- API integration is done using axios.
- This application fetches, creates, updates and deletes posts.

Link https://github.com/parkarsayali/memoriesApp

01/02/2021 - 01/03/2021

Zomato clone application

- I have built 'zomato-clone' food delivery application from scratch.
- I have used HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and React|s for the interactive and attractive front-end.
- And for the backend I have used Nodejs, express and mongoDB

Link https://github.com/parkarsayali/zomato--replica

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Poetry

- I enjoy reading and writing free verse poetry.
- My work is featured in Various Indian magazines like 'Delhi Poetry Slam', 'By me Poetry' and International literary magazine 'Genre:Urban Arts'
- I've published two poetry chapbooks namely '41 Petals', and 'Dust used to be other things'

Link https://www.amazon.in/Poetry-Sayali-Parkar-Literature-Fiction/s?rh=n%3A1318175031%2Cp 27%3ASayali+Parkar_

CERTIFICATION

01/01/2021 - 30/04/2021

Edureka MERN stack Internship

Write here the description...